Contact

8200 N MacArthur Blvd Irving, TX 75063 1 (469) 713-1655 (Work) yvmgilrn@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/yvonne-gilrn-05563180 (LinkedIn) www.familyER.com (Company)

Top Skills

Emergency Nursing
Healthcare Management
Patient Safety

Languages

English Spanish

Certifications ACLS

Yvonne Gil, RN

Facility Administrator and Nurse Manager Emergency Care Center ER & Urgent Care

Houston, Texas

Summary

Experienced Administrator with a demonstrated history of working in the hospital & health care industry. Built 5 FSED from ground up, including licensing, hiring and governing board member. Skilled in Pediatric Advanced Life Support (PALS), Emergency Medicine, TNCC, and Advanced Cardiac Life Support (ACLS). Certified Emergency Nurse (CEN). Strong healthcare professional with an Associates in Health Science of Nursing focused in Emergency Nursing from Houston Community College. Currently working on Bachelors In Health Science of Nursing focused on Hospital Administration from University of Texas at Arlington.

I also have up to date policies and procedures for FSED, including Lab and Radiology. If you are a start-up and need assistance with compliance, feel free to reach out.

Experience

Emergency Center
Nursing
August 2008 - Present (11 years 10 months)
Houston, Texas Area

Texas Emergency Care Center Administrator April 2016 - August 2019 (3 years 5 months) Irving, TX

OnCall Emergency Centers, LLC 5 years 6 months VP Chief Nursing Officer 2015 - August 2019 (4 years)

Director Of Nursing

March 2014 - August 2019 (5 years 6 months) Texas

Director of Nursing at new Start-up Emergency Center located in Memorial Village of Houston and Circle-C of Austin, Texas. Now hiring all departments: Nursing, ER Tech, Rad Tech, and Registration/PAS at both locations. Send resumes to jobs@MyER247.com.

Methodist Health System ER Nurse 2005 - 2013 (8 years)

Ben Taub General Hospital Trauma Nurse August 2003 - August 2005 (2 years 1 month) Houston Area, Texas

Education

Houston Community College
Associates in Health Science of Nursing, Nursing (2000 - 2003)

The University of Texas at Arlington
Bachelor of Applied Science (B.A.Sc.), Registered Nursing/Registered
Nurse · (2005)